I was in a fireside chat recently, and the person who was interviewing me asked me a question
about the increased levels of burnout and decreased wellbeing that so many people have experienced.
And she said to me, how do we get to the light at the end of the tunnel?
How do we get to this light where we feel well and happy?
And I thought about this a little bit, and I wanted to share this reflection with you,
which is that when we are in the tunnel, we don't need to be racing for the light.
Part of being in the tunnel, this tunnel of exhaustion or depletion is also recognising
that the tunnel has sides, that we can lean against the side of the tunnel and take
a breath.
We can sit on the floor and we can cry.
We can name our emotions in the tunnel, the disappointment or the loneliness, and we can
ask ourselves, what is the value, what is the need that is being sign-posted by that
emotional experience?
We can reach out for other people's hands in the tunnel, and we can just hold those
hands metaphorically, knowing that we are not alone.
I've come to realise that so much of well-being is not about grasping for the light.
So much of well-being is about learning how to see in the dark.